Software Engineer

SUMMARY

I am a full stack software engineer with a passion for collaborative tools, distributed systems, and cloud computing. I design, implement, and scale distributed systems and have multiple years of experience building software with proficiency in Ruby, Rails, Node, JavaScript, Git, Linux, and RESTful APIs.

EXPERIENCE

SpaceCraft (https://spacecraft-repl.github.io/)

Software Engineer Brooklyn, NY October 2018 - Present

- Co-created and deployed an open-source, real-time, collaborative REPL.
- Built a network architecture that scales allows multiple users to collaborate in a private session.
- Developed real-time synchronization for input/output for collaborating users.
- Created a container architecture to isolate user sessions, prevent malicious attacks, and limit session resources.
- Implemented a reverse proxy to scale the application to dozens of concurrent users and sessions.
- Wrote a detailed case study (https://spacecraft-repl.github.io/whitepaper).

Freelance Fullstack Engineer

Full Stack Engineer Brooklyn, NY April 2017 - September 2018

 Built an extensive list of open-source contributions, personal full stack web applications, and a Ruby gem.

SpaceCraft Proxy Server

- A reverse proxy server built from scratch using Node.js and the Docker API.
- Manages multiple user sessions, initializes containers, and forwards clients' requests to the appropriate container.

Reaction

• List management productivity app with that allows users to create, delete, label, and organize cards and lists, and supports scheduling and tagging.

Lander

 A Ruby gem that allows developers to easily log data structures for solving coding challenges.

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

Back-End: Node, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs

Front-End: JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS

Other: Git, Linux, Docker, WebSockets, Distributed Systems, Heroku

EXTRACURRICULAR

Technical Blog Writer

February 2018 - Present

I've written 5 articles on software engineering topics with ~2700 views.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX, September 2010 - May 2015 B.S. in Physics